International Confederation of Free Trade Unions Records on Microfilm 5272 mf
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
International Confederation of Free Trade Unions Records on Microfilm
1954-1955
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
International Confederation of Free Trade Unions (ICFTU)
5272 mf
0.11 cubic feet
1 microfilm reel
Records (documents), microfilm.
This collection contains agendas and minutes of the Asian Regional Committee's Executive Board, reports of the Regional Secretary, and reports and other materials about trade unionism in Asia.
8859947
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, September 26, 2012
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, February 23, 2017
Biographical / Historical
The ICFTU established regional organizations to strengthen operations in the various geographic areas. The regional organizations were to promote harmony and cooperation between all types of trade unions which were free agencies of the workers. While they enjoyed a high degree of autonomy, they were at the same time responsible to the ICFTU for their actions. The Asian Regional Organization had jurisdiction in all the countries of Asia and the Far East.
The regional organization was to:
1. Secure new affiliations
2. Assist existing trade unions and promote the establishment of new ones.
3. Organize regional conferences and discuss problems
4. Coordinate activities
5. Collect and distribute data about working and social conditions
6. Advise the ICFTU on regional problems, implement its policy and carry on publicity for it.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5010: International Confederation of Free Trade Unions Records 5010: International Confederation of Free Trade Unions Records 5582: Archives Foreign File (AFF)
International labor activities.; International Confederation of Free Trade Unions.
8859947
- Financial Statement for the Year 1 January to 31 December 1954, 1 (Reel 1)
  Scope and Contents
  2 pp
  - Appendix I: Balance Sheet as at 31st December 1954, 1 (Reel 1)
  - Appendix II: Income and Expenditure Account for the Period 1st January 1954 to 31st December 1954, 1 (Reel 1)
  - Affiliation fees for 1954, 1 (Reel 1)
    9 pp
- Requests for Reductions in Affiliation Fees, 2 (Reel 1)
- Minutes of the 13th Meeting of the Executive Board (Paris, 24-28 November 1954), 3 (Reel 1)
  20 pp
  - Appendix: Committee on Publications, Publicity and Education, 1954; 3 (Reel 1)
  - Appendix: Committee on Finance, Staff and Organization, 1954; 3 (Reel 1)
  - Appendix: Committee on Economic and Social Questions, 1954; 3 (Reel 1)
    4 pp
  - Appendix: Committee on Revision of the UN Charter, 1954; 3 (Reel 1)
  - Appendix: Committee on Forced Labor, 1954; 3 (Reel 1)
  - Appendix: Committee on Regional Activities, 1954; 3 (Reel 1)
    7 pp
- Minutes of the 7th Meeting of the Emergency Committee (Brussels, 1-2 February 1955), 4 (Reel 1)
  15 pp
- Applications for Affiliation, 5 (Reel 1)
- Memo on the Structure of the ICFTU, 6 (Reel 1)
  3 pp
- General Secretary's Report on Activities, 7 (Reel 1)
  30 pp
- Report of the 11th Meeting of the Regional Activities Fund Committee (Brussels, 14-16 March 1955), 8 (Reel 1)
  11 pp
  - Appendix: Summary of Income Received up to 28 February 1955, 8 (Reel 1)
    5 pp
  - Appendix: Summary of Expenditure up to 31 December 1954, 8 (Reel 1)
    1 pp
- Response to the Appeal for 1 US Cent per Member Voluntary Contribution for Regional Activities for the Year Beginning 7/1/55, 1955; 9 (Reel 1)
- Report of the Asian Regional Organization for the Period 1 October 1954-31 March 1955, 1954-1955; 10 (Reel 1)
  13 pp
- Preliminary Report on and Summary of Decisions Taken by the 3rd Congress of ORIT (San Jose, Costa Rica, 13-17 April 1955), 11 (Reel 1)
  - Appendix: Budget for 1955, 11 (Reel 1)
  - Appendix: Affiliation Fees, 1955; 11 (Reel 1)
  - Appendix: Certain Decisions of the ORIT Executive Committee, 1955; 11 (Reel 1)
- Preliminary Report on the 2nd Conference of the Caribbean Area Division (CADORIT), (Port-of-Spain, Trinidad, 6-8 April 1955), 12 (Reel 1)
  - Appendix: List of Participants, 1955; 12 (Reel 1)
  - Appendix: CADORIT Action Programme, 1955; 12 (Reel 1)
- Report on Mission to Colombia by H. Horne, 13 (Reel 1)
- Report of the European Regional Organization for the Period 1 October 1954-31 March 1955, 1954-1955; 14 (Reel 1)
- Report on Visit to Morocco by Omer Becu and J.H. Oldenbroek, 15 (Reel 1)
  - Appendix: Supplementary Note, 15 (Reel 1)
  - Appendix: Recommendations of the ILO Governing Body (128th Session) Concerning Trade Union Rights in Morocco, 15 (Reel 1)
  - Appendix: Morrocan Trade Unionistst who are Unable to Exercise Their Trade Union Functions, 15 (Reel 1)
  - Appendix: "Suppressed" Part of Speech by M. July, Minister for Moroccan and Tunisian Affairs, 15 (Reel 1)
- Report of First Mission to the Middle East by N. Boudali, 16 (Reel 1)
- Memo on Joint ICFTU-ILO Workers' Group Committee, 17 (Reel 1)
- Proposals from Affiliated Organizations, 18 (Reel 1)